The Hundred-Thousand Demon Drop?
（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）百千夜叉墜(ひゃくせんやしゃおとし)を…
（火ノ丸）本物の必殺に？
You'll hone it into a real weapon?
（駿海(しゅんかい)）…で どうすんだ？
What do you say?
Will you let me train you or not?
俺の指導を
受けるのか受けねえのか？
Make a decision!
（駿海）はっきりしやがれ！
（火ノ丸）ンンッ…
I'll do anything to become stronger.
強くなれるなら何だってする
ワシに稽古をつけてください！
Please train me!
How long are you in Nagoya for?
名古屋(なごや)には いつまでいるんだ？
One week.
（火ノ丸）１週間です
Okay. Then, you two will be spending
the whole week here with me.
（駿海）
よ〜し　今日から お前らは
ここに１週間 泊まり込みな
Huh?
（礼奈(れいな)）はぁ！？
いや こいつは分かるけど—
I get why you're keeping him here,
but why do I have to stay, too?
私も？　なんで？
俺の弟子になるにあたって
ひとつ約束してもらう
You must promise me one thing
before I take you on as my apprentice.
That goes for you too, young lady.
お嬢ちゃんもだ
You will do exactly what
I tell you to, without complaint.
（駿海）俺の言うことは黙って従え
いちいち理由を尋ねるのは禁止だ
You will refrain from
asking me to explain myself.
You got that?
いいな？
Bout 13
"100-yen-coin Training"
That man... Who was he?
（千鶴子(ちづこ)）さっきの人は
どういう人なんですか？
（冴ノ山(さえのやま)）うん？
From your reaction, I'm guessing
he must be someone important.
（千鶴子）皆さんの
反応を見るに—
すごい人なのは分かるのですが…
"Important" is an understatement.
すごいなんてもんじゃないですよ
He's getting on in years now,
so Ushio-kun didn't recognize him.
だいぶ お年を召されたので
潮(うしお)君も気づかなかったようですが
He's a former yokozuna
by the name of Shunkai.
（冴ノ山）元横綱 駿海
His skill as a sumo wrestler
in his prime goes without saying,
現役時代の実力は
言わずもがなですが—
but he's also known as a great trainer,
guiding two wrestlers to the rank of yokozuna.
２人の横綱を育てた
名指導者としても知られています
あっ…　横綱を２人も？
Two yokozuna?
What a strange turn of events.
（力士Ａ）しっかし
どういう風の吹き回しだろうな
I heard he quit the association
and walked away from sumo.
（力士Ａ）協会も辞めて
相撲からは遠ざかっていたと聞くが
Think that kid's gonna be okay?
（力士Ｂ）あの子 大丈夫か？
ウワサどおりなら
俺は３日で逃げ出す自信あるぜ
If the rumors about the old man
are true, I wouldn't last three days.
Same here.
（力士Ｃ）俺も
（力士たち）うん？
（典馬(てんま)）お疲れさんでございます
Thanks for all your hard work.
Oh, he's finally shown up.
（力士Ｂ）おう　来たな
They may both be national treasures,
but they look totally different.
（力士Ａ）
同じ国宝でも こうも違うか
This guy's tall enough to
tower over the sekitori.
（冴ノ山）関取衆を見下ろす上背
ひと目で逸材と分かる
A single glance tells you
he's a real diamond.
Thanks for having me.
（典馬）よろしくお願いします
なるほど　潮君も焦るわけだ
I can see why Ushio-kun was
in such a rush to improve.
Training with a former yokozuna...
元横綱の指導
Futomaru Supermarket
Even the sekitori were intimidated by him.
関取衆も恐れるような人
一体 どんな猛稽古が…
What terrifying trials has
he got in store for him?
Super
Cheap
Special Sale
（女性）押さないで！
There's no way we'll be able to do this.
ねえ やっぱムリだって
We don't have a choice.
やるしかねえよ
もう稽古は始まっとるんじゃ！
Our training's already started!
ウオ〜ッ！　ンンッ…
ここか？　ここか？
Here? What about here?
Here!
H-How can you call this training?!
こ… これの どこが稽古なのよ？
Your first task is to fetch us some food.
まず最初の稽古は腹ごしらえだ
I want curry.
（駿海）カレーが食いてえ
それで 30分以内に人数分 用意しな
You have 30 minutes to serve up
enough for the three of us.
Yes, sir!
（火ノ丸）はい！
（礼奈）はぁ！？
Huh?!
You can't make curry
on a 100-yen budget.
100円でカレーなんてムリでしょう
しかも 30分って…
And a 30-minute time limit?
He said using your head
was part of the training.
考えるのも稽古のうちと言っていた
きっと正解はある
So there must be a way.
You make me wait this long
and this is what you produce?
（駿海）
さんざん待たせて これかよ
M-My apologies.
す… すいません
No toppings, and you
missed your deadline.
（駿海）
具もねえし 時間も大幅に過ぎてる
This doesn't make the grade.
不合格だ
（礼奈）
犬の散歩に 花の水やりに 洗濯
Walk his dog, water his
flowers, do his laundry...
What about actual sumo?!
つうか 相撲は？
雑用ばっかで日が暮れちゃったよ
The sun went down while
we were stuck doing chores!
Th-This is all part of the training.
こ… これも稽古じゃ
（駿海）なんだよ
全然 終わってねえじゃねえか
What's this? You're not done yet?
M-My apologies!
（火ノ丸）す… すいません！
（駿海）まあいいや
Whatever. Just get the area around
the sumo ring ready for use.
さっさと 土俵周りだけでも
使えるようにしとけ
Huh?
Don't give me that.
（駿海）“えっ”じゃねえよ
相撲見てやるっつってんの
I'm saying I wish to see your sumo.
Y-Yes, sir!
は… はい！
Finally.
やっとか…
（戸の開閉音）
（岩竜(がんりゅう)）お疲れさんでございます
Good work, one and all.
Yeah.
（駿海）おう　呼びつけて悪いね
Sorry for making you come out here.
The fifth-ranked west
maegashira, Ganryu-zeki!
西前頭(にしまえがしら)五枚目 岩竜関！
例の三点投げ 関取に見せてやれ
Show this sekitori that
triple combo of yours.
はい！
Yes, sir!
See? Don't you think that's an
interesting move, sekitori?
なっ？　面白(おもしれ)え技だろう？　関取
（駿海）さて 小鬼よ
（火ノ丸）はい！
Okay, little demon.
Yes, sir!
（駿海）
お前は その三点投げで勝て
Use your triple combo to win a bout.
それ以外の決まり手は認めん
You cannot win using any other technique.
（火ノ丸）えっ？　あっ はい
（岩竜）ンンッ…
Uh, yes, sir.
（礼奈）それだけ？
何のアドバイスもなし？
That's all you're telling him?
You've got no advice for him?
He knows the element of surprise
is gone once the other guy's seen it.
（礼奈）一度見せたら通じないのは
分かってるのに…
This is no different from
the practice session earlier.
これじゃ
昼間の稽古の繰り返しじゃない
15分たったな　今日は ここまで
It's been 15 minutes.
That's all for today.
えっ？　もう終わり？　くそ！
It's over already?
Damn it!
Here are your bags.
（桐仁(きりひと)）これ ２人の荷物
How are you finding the former
yokozuna's training methods?
どうだ？　元横綱の指導は
（礼奈）どうもこうもないよ！
何なの？　あのじじい
You can't even call it training!
Who does that old coot think he is?
He was the one who made the offer,
but he doesn't even do anything!
自分が誘ったくせに
全然 やる気ないんだもん
I think we should just call it quits.
私は
もうやめたほうがいいと思うけどね
This was only the first day.
まだ初日じゃ
And besides, if I backed out now,
それに何より
このまま帰ったんじゃ—
I'd leave with nothing but regrets.
悔しさしか残らん
Watch over Hinomaru.
（桐仁）火ノ丸を頼みます
えっ？　そんなこと言われても…
Easy for you to say.
Shunkai-san sure lived up to the rumors.
（岩竜）ウワサどおりの人だったな
駿海さんは
I feel sorry for that kid
he's taken under his wing.
あの子も かわいそうに
目ぇつけられちまって
He's just making him do absurd things
so he can enjoy the spectacle.
ムチャぶりして困ってるサマを見て
楽しんでるだけなんだよ　あの人は
They say he turned two
wrestlers into yokozuna,
横綱を２人育てたなんて
言われてるけど—
but they must just have been
talented from the start.
もともと その２人に
才能があったってだけ
There were plenty more young wrestlers
むしろ あの横暴な振る舞いに
嫌気が差して—
who couldn't cope with his
oppressive behavior and took off.
去っていた若手のほうが
はるかに多いよ
See? That's what I was saying!
（礼奈）ほら　だから言ったじゃん
And then, there's that kid.
（岩竜）あの子も あの子だ
Most people would've
realized all this by now.
普通は
気づきそうなもんなんだけどな
And what's with that technique of his?
それに 何だよ？　あの技は
This isn't acrobatics.
曲芸じゃあるまいし
必死も度を超えると笑っちゃうよ
It's beyond desperate and laughable.
Hmm?
（水をかける音）
（岩竜）ウワッ！
M-My apologies!
（岩竜）す… すいません！
いや 駿海さんを悪く言うつもりは
I didn't mean to badmouth you, Shunkai-san.
I don't care what you say about me.
（駿海）俺のことは いいんだよ
But you'd better make sure I don't
catch you laughing at that boy.
でもな
あの小僧を笑うのは許さねえ
恵まれた体格に あぐらをかいてる
お前らには分かるまい
Because you two are blessed with large
frames, you will never understand.
With the body that boy has got, that
technique is his only means of survival.
あの技はな 小僧が あの体で—
死にものぐるいで見つけた
生きる道なんだ
Tell me what's so funny about that!
あいつの何が おかしいのか
言ってみろ！
Never laugh at someone
who's giving their all!
必死なヤツを笑うんじゃねえよ！
Super Non
Now he expects us to make an
eight-veggie stir fry on a 100-yen budget?
（礼奈）今度は100円で八宝菜？
ムリムリ　最近 野菜 高いんだから
Can't be done. The price
of vegetables keeps going up.
Maybe this 100-yen coin is me...
恐らく この百円玉がワシで—
and the eight-veggie stir fry is my goal:
the Hundred-Thousand Demon Drop.
到達点である八宝菜が
百千夜叉墜という謎かけ…
（火ノ丸）…なのかもしれん
（礼奈）はぁ？
It's a riddle of some sort.
Huh?
Whatever the case,
I'm gonna put my faith in him!
（火ノ丸）
とにかくワシは あの人を信じる！
Even if he asks for the impossible,
どんな無理難題だって
やり遂げると決めたんじゃ！
Shibakiyama Stable
I've decided I'm seeing this through!
あっ…　もう…
Jeez...
（駿海）随分 質素だな
Looks rather plain.
What you've got there is a one,
two, three-veggie stir fry.
これじゃ １ ２…
“三宝菜(さんぽうさい)”じゃねえか
（火ノ丸）す… すいません
M-My apologies.
B-But it tastes a lot better than the curry.
で… でも
味は だいぶマシになりましたから
How it tastes is not important.
（駿海）
味なんて どうだっていいんだよ
I gave you 100 yen and 30 minutes to
produce an eight-veggie stir fry, yes?
“百円玉で
八宝菜を30分以内に用意しろ”
俺は そう言ったよな
Something's bothering you, young lady.
（駿海）
何か言いたげだな お嬢ちゃん
（礼奈）えっ？　いや その…
No, I, um...
Out with it. You have my permission.
言ってみろ　許可する
Is this really going to help him?
本当に これでいいんですか？
I think it'd be more effective
to just tell him what to do.
直接 口で言ってあげたほうが
効率的だと思うんですが
Spelling it out is the easy option.
口で言うのは簡単だ
And if I did that, he'd even feel
like he understood, for a while.
言えば いっとき
頭で分かった気になるだろう
ただ そうやって
簡単に手に入れた知識は軽い
But gaining knowledge in
that way is a fleeting triumph.
The significance of it doesn't sink in.
ホントの意味で
身に着きはしないのさ
回りくどいやり方に
見えるかもしれんが 己で考え—
This may seem like a roundabout
way of doing things,
but thinking for yourself and
working hard toward an end goal
苦労して たどりついた答えこそが
生き抜くための—
becomes a technique in itself
that allows you to survive.
技になるんだ
（典馬）シュ〜ッ！
（冴ノ山）ウッ！　ンンッ…
One more bout, please, Saenoyama-zeki.
（典馬）
もう一番 お願いします 冴ノ山関
（冴ノ山）ハァ…
Let's take five and clean off this dirt.
いったん下がって
泥を落としましょう
土俵は私たちだけのものじゃない
This sumo ring is for everyone to use.
Worrying about what other sumo
wrestlers want won't make us stronger.
ほかの力士に気ぃ遣ってたら
強くなんてなれないでしょう
（冴ノ山）では
あの人に お願いしたら どうです？
Then, isn't there someone
else you should be asking?
He'd be a better opponent for you.
私より適任でしょうに
I'm talking about your brother,
Daikeisho, the ozeki.
君のお兄さん　大関 大景勝(だいけいしょう)
I don't want to fight him.
（典馬）あの人とは やりたくない
（冴ノ山）嫌いなんですか？
Do you hate him?
Not really.
（典馬）
別に　兄のことは尊敬してる
I respect my brother.
Since becoming an ozeki, he hasn't
ended a season with a losing record.
大関になってから
一度も負け越したことはないし—
実力はトップクラスだ
He's right up there, in terms of ability.
But the strength of the yokozuna
has broken him.
でも あの人は 横綱の強さに
ホントは折れちまってんだ
He knows everyone has high hopes for him,
誰より期待されてることを
知りながら—
but he's given up on becoming a yokozuna.
横綱になることを諦めちまってる
It's disgusting.
最低だろう
I'm not like my brother.
（典馬）俺は兄とは違う
I'll live up to any and all expectations.
どんな期待も背負って
応えてみせる
Expectations?
（冴ノ山）期待？
I won't just surpass Tennoji and Kuze...
（典馬）天王寺(てんのうじ)でも久世(くぜ)でもない
I will take my brother's place
and become the strongest yokozuna.
兄に代わって
俺が最強の横綱になるんだ
（力士Ａ）
そういえば あの小さいの
今ごろ どうしてんだろうな
What's that shrimp up to now?
He's still training with Shunkai-san, working
solely on improving that technique of his.
（岩竜）
相変わらず 駿海さんとこで—
バカのひとつ覚えみたいに
あの技 鍛えてますよ
（典馬）駿海？　元横綱？
Shunkai? The former yokozuna?
Tell me more about what they're doing.
（典馬）
その話 詳しく聞かせてくれよ
Another day of nothing but chores.
今日も雑用で
１日終わっちゃった
But look at the size of this bath.
しかし 大きなお風呂
横綱って お金あるんだ？
Yokozuna must be loaded.
So why does he only give us
a 100-yen coin each time?
なのに どうして
100円しか出してくれないの？
Damn that old man!
あのじじい！
That's quite the monologue.
（駿海）でっけえ独り言だな
（礼奈）ハッ…
What are you doing out there?! You pervert!
（礼奈）なんで
そんな所にいるんですか　変態！
I'll go where I like. It's my house.
俺ん家(ち)で どこにいようと
俺の勝手だろう
Though, I must say...
しかし お前さんも
意外と頑張るじゃねえか
You're working harder
than I expected you to.
Well, if I left, he wouldn't be
able to train here anymore.
だって 私が帰ったら—
あいつの修業も
打ち切られちゃうんでしょう？
You've taken a real liking to him, eh?
（駿海）ホレてんだね あいつに
（礼奈）ンッ…　はぁ！？
Don't be stupid! It's not like that!
なにバカ言って…
私は そんなんじゃ…
I have, too.
（駿海）俺も そうさ
あいつの相撲は人を引き付ける
His style of sumo inspires people.
Oh, he was talking about sumo?
アア…　相撲の話か
You aren't normally
interested in sumo, are you?
お前さんだって ふだんは
相撲に興味なんてねえだろう？
Huh?
But you want to see him in the ring.
（駿海）なのに あいつの相撲は
見たくなる　違うか？
Am I wrong?
I don't blame you.
ムリもねえ
His style of sumo has a simple charm to it
that you don't see in professional sumo.
あいつの相撲は 今の大相撲では
お目にかかれない—
単純明快な痛快さがあるからな
Seeing a small guy throwing someone huge
would get anyone's blood pumping.
小せえヤツが
でけえヤツを ぶん投げる
こんなの
ワクワクしねえわけがねえ
俺や お前が
あいつに協力を惜しまないのも—
I think the reason both you
and I are so willing to help him
is because we're dreaming with him.
きっと あいつに
夢を見てるからなんだろう
Help? But I...
協力って 私…
別に何もしてないけど
I'm not really doing anything.
That's not true.
（駿海）そんなことはねえさ
お前は今 ここにいる
You're here, aren't you?
For better or worse, he's got a thick skull.
あいつは
よくも悪くも頭が固すぎてな
いかにも
要領のよさそうなお前さんと—
You seem pretty smart,
so I figured you'd make a good team.
足して割るぐらいが ちょうどいい
That's why I asked you to stay here, too.
そう思って お前も呼んだんだ
お前さんが あいつに
影響を受けているように—
Just as you've been influenced by him,
I want him to feel something from you, too.
あいつも お前さんから
何かを感じてほしいんだがね
Where did you go at this time of night?
（礼奈）
どこ行ってたの？　こんな時間に
Oh, I was on the phone with Kirihito.
（火ノ丸）
ああ　ちょっと桐仁と電話を
And in preparation for tomorrow,
I picked up every sales flyer I could find!
あと あしたに備えて—
安売りのチラシを
片っ端から かき集めてきた
うわ…　そんなの
スマホで調べれば 一発なのに
You could've just pulled up the deals
on a smartphone, you know.
（火ノ丸）おお！　へえ…
こんな方法があるんじゃのぅ
There was another way to do it, huh?
You're incredible!
（火ノ丸）お前 すごいな
（礼奈）すごくない
No, I'm not.
The world's bigger than you think.
あんたが思ってる以上に
世の中 いろいろあんのよ
電話だって言えば貸すのに
わざわざ公衆電話なんて…
Also, you didn't have to go find a pay phone.
I would've let you borrow mine.
You can ask me for help, you know.
少しは 私のことも頼りなさいよ
I mean, I... I'm your manager, after all.
私だって その…
マ… マネージャーなんだからね
Huh? Wait, what?!
（礼奈）えっ？　ちょ…　なに！？
Thanks, Reina!
（火ノ丸）ありがとうよ 礼奈！
（礼奈）へっ？
Huh?
Aren't you going to help today?
（駿海）
今日は手伝わなくていいのか？
You've only got 100 yen and 30 minutes
to serve me tempura over rice.
100円で天丼を30分以内だぞ
あ〜 なんか今日は
自信があるみたいで…
He seemed pretty confident
about today's challenge.
（駿海）ほう…
（礼奈）うん？
（典馬）お疲れさんでございます
Good work.
（駿海）うん？　何か用か？
Do you need something?
You've turned two wrestlers into yokozuna,
（典馬）横綱２人を育てた名指導者
and more importantly, you have
the experience of being one yourself.
そして 何より自身が
横綱になった その経験で—
I want you to train me, Shunkai-san.
俺に稽古をつけてくれよ　駿海さん
I'm back—
（火ノ丸）
ただいま戻りま…　日景(ひかげ)典馬！
Hikage Tenma!
なんで てめえが ここに？
What are you doing here?!
I'm not here for you, Onimaru.
（典馬）お前に用はないよ　鬼丸(おにまる)
Who is this guy? Do you know him?
何なのよ？　知り合い？
We had an unofficial bout the other day.
こないだ
ちょっと野良試合をしてな
Hikage...
（駿海）日景…　そうか お前か
大関 大景勝の弟ってのは
Oh, I know who you are.
You're the ozeki Daikeisho's brother.
So you must already know
I have a bad reputation.
だったら
俺の悪評も耳にしてるはずだが
The closer to the top they are,
the worse things they say about me.
角界の中心に近いヤツほど
俺のことを悪く言うからな
I don't care about any of that.
そんなもん関係ない
If I don't think your training
is worthwhile, I'll just leave.
俺が この稽古は役に立たないと
判断すれば 切るだけだから
Now, hang on a minute!
（礼奈）ちょっと待ってよ！
What makes you think
you can say that? Get in line!
あとから来て
なに勝手なこと言ってんの？
I'm telling him he should drop this guy
and make me his apprentice instead.
そいつは やめて 俺のことを
弟子にしろって言ってんだよ
What?
（火ノ丸）ンンッ…
（駿海）あのな お前さん
Listen, young man.
That's not how you go about
asking to become an apprentice.
さっきから
弟子になろうって態度じゃねえぜ
俺が お前を教えたいか
どうかってのも大事だろう
Don't forget, I'm the one
who has to decide to train you.
Of course.
（典馬）もちろん
It's the duty of the apprentice
to win over his master.
ホレさせるのが弟子の役目さ
I'll show you who is the more
deserving apprentice in the sumo ring.
こいつと俺と
どっちが弟子として魅力的か—
土俵の上で証明する
I'm just not sure whether the coward who
was afraid of me will accept the challenge.
ただ 俺にビビった腰抜けに
受ける度胸があるかが問題だけどな
Sounds good to me.
（握りしめる音）
（火ノ丸）望むところじゃ
You idiot!
（駿海）バカ野郎！
（礼奈）えっ？
Little demon, you're letting
my good intentions go to waste.
小鬼　てめえは今 俺の善意を
踏みにじろうとしてるんだぞ
まだ三点投げの途中だろうが
You haven't perfected your
triple combo technique.
Go ahead and accept
if you want, but I'll kick you out!
この勝負を受けてみろ
その時点で てめえは破門だ！
Then, permit me to fight.
（火ノ丸）なら 許可をください
He and I were going to
end up like this eventually.
（火ノ丸）
こいつとは いずれ こうなってた
In our first bout, I was afraid of him,
１度目の勝負で こいつに
ビビった あのときのワシと—
決別しなきゃいけねえ
and I need to bury my old self.
Just as I have trusted and followed you,
ワシが あなたを信じて
やってきたように—
I am asking you to trust me, master.
あなたも
ワシを信じてください 師匠
I will win this bout with the
Hundred-Thousand Demon Drop!
この勝負 百千夜叉墜で勝ちます！
フン…
Win me over, huh?
（駿海）“ホレさせる”か
Over two meters tall,
with long arms and broad shoulders.
２メートルを超える長身
長い腕に 広い肩幅
If his torso was slightly longer,
he'd be the perfect build.
もう少し胴が長けりゃ 正に理想的
He does evoke a different kind of
excitement than the little demon does.
確かに小鬼とは違う意味で
そそる素材だ
（礼奈）ほ… 本当に…
（駿海）うん？
Will we...
...really have to leave if he loses?
負けたら終わりなんですかね？
（駿海）知らねえよ
あいつらが言いだしたことだ
Don't ask me.
That's just something they said.
Either way, if you can't talk big,
いずれにせよ 大口たたくぐらいの
気概がなきゃ—
you won't get anywhere near
the rank of yokozuna.
横綱には かすりもしねえ
（駿海）はっきよい！
（火ノ丸）グッ！
Spirit!
フゥ〜…
（駿海）あっ…
（礼奈）な… なに その威力！
What's with that power?
In this era, size means everything.
And you've been forsaken by it.
大型化の時代に
取り残されたお前に—
You will never have a career
in the sumo ring!
土俵で生きる道はねえ！
I've been here a few days now.
ここに来て数日間 相撲から
遠ざかったおかげで気づけた
Taking a step back from
sumo has helped me notice...
右肘だけじゃない
It's not just my right elbow.
休ませた全身から 力が みなぎる！
My whole body is welling with power
now that it's well rested!
（火ノ丸）おら！
（典馬）クッ…
その体に似合わぬ強力(ごうりき)も
小鬼本来の魅力のひとつよ
That rigidity which defies
his physique is one thing
that makes the little
demon so interesting.
Good, he's getting in close—
よし！　内に入っ…
Last time, I let you grab my mawashi
belt so I could see your triple combo.
（典馬）前回は三点投げ見たさに
廻しをくれてやったけど—
But I won't be playing
around this time, Onimaru!
今回は遊びはなしだ 鬼丸！
He can hit a target so low
and small with such intensity, huh?
あの低くて小さい的に
あれだけの威力で打ち込めるのか
Hey!
そんな…
Forget landing the Hundred-Thousand Demon Drop!
（礼奈）
百千夜叉墜を決めるどころか…
He's not even close to grabbing his belt!
どんどん廻しが遠ざかる
（火ノ丸）おら！
（典馬）ンンッ…
You want to hit back?
（典馬）俺と突き合う気か？
Don't underestimate me!
（典馬）ナメるな！
（火ノ丸）ンンッ…
ナメとるのは どっちじゃ？
大典太(おおでんた)
Who's underestimating who, Odenta?
I was the one who grabbed
the untouchable mawashi belt
ワシは あの
廻しを取られぬ国宝—
of national treasure, Mikazuki Munechika!
三日月宗近(みかづきむねちか)から
廻しを奪った男じゃ！
Yes!
（礼奈）よっしゃ！
Now, show me
さあ 見せてみろ
the answer you've come up with!
お前が出した答えを
The ridiculous difference in our heights
（典馬）このバカげた身長差が
可能にする—
allows him to do a shoulder throw
while holding my mawashi belt.
いわば 廻しを持っての背負い投げ
It's a fearsome technique,
確かに恐ろしい技だが
この３点目こそ諸刃(もろは)の剣
but the third contact point
makes it a double-edged sword.
If I avoid his leg sweep,
この足技さえ透かしてしまえば
今日が三点投げの命日だ！
today will mark the end
of the triple combo throw!
I'll push you into the ground!
（典馬）このまま押しつぶす！
フェイント！？
It was a feint?!
ヤバイ！　体が浮いちまった！
Oh, no! He's lifted me off the ground!
Reverse Hundred Demon Throw!
Reverse
Hundred
Demon
Throw
クッ…　てめえ！
バカにすんじゃねえ！
Damn you...
Don't mock me!
Maybe I did get cocky because
of the power of that technique.
（火ノ丸）ワシは 技の威力に
浮かれていたのかもしれん
The Hundred-Thousand Demon Drop is
difficult, but if I can pull it off, I win.
“百千夜叉墜は難しい
だが 出せば勝てる”
Thinking like that made
my sumo predictable.
その思いが
ワシの相撲を単調にしていた
That's right.
そうじゃ
いろいろ方法はあるんじゃ
There are plenty of ways...
...to initiate the Hundred-Thousand Demon Drop!
百千夜叉墜に至る道も
ひとつじゃない！
Not just one!
I can't get out of this stance!
（典馬）体勢が…　動けない！
Before executing the technique,
you must first set up your opponent.
技を決めるには
その前の崩しこそが重要
If they're off-balance, they can't
counter it, even if they know it's coming.
崩しさえすれば 最後の一手は
分かっていても避けられない
Now that you're looking at the big picture,
視界が開けた今
技の組み合わせは 正に無限大
there's no limit to the number of ways
you can set up your technique.
Like the name suggests,
その名のとおり 百千の鬼に
墜(お)とされる必殺と相なった
it has become an army of a hundred-thousand
demons to send him crashing to the ground!
His style of sumo inspires people.
（駿海）
あいつの相撲は人を引き付ける
Seeing a small guy throwing someone huge
would get anyone's blood pumping.
小せえヤツが
でけえヤツを ぶん投げる
そんなの
ワクワクしねえわけがねえ
Hundred-Thousand Demon Drop!
Hundred
Thou
sand
Hundred
Demon
sand
Thou
Drop
Demon
sand
Drop
Demon
Splendid.
お見事
ようやく
正解に たどりついたようだな
It seems you've finally found the answer.
Yes, sir.
（火ノ丸）はい
And from the look of things,
you've solved the food riddle as well.
さて その様子だと
メシの謎かけも解けたんだろう？
（火ノ丸）はい
Yes, sir.
The challenge you gave me
師匠のお題は こうです
was to take that 100-yen coin and
come back with tempura over rice.
“百円玉で天丼を用意しろ”
You didn't say anything
about buying or making it.
買えとも作れとも言ってない
So all I had to do was...
なら ワシがやるべきことは…
Ten
Hello! Your tempura takeout,
courtesy of Tenemon.
（店員）
毎度！　天丼屋の天右衛門(てんえもん)です
Could you pick up the tab, master?
さあ お会計お願いします　師匠
You cheeky little...
生意気な口利きやがって この野郎
文句なしの合格だよ　火ノ丸
You've passed with
flying colors, Hinomaru!
あの…　誰か出迎えるなら
私たちだけでも…
Um...
You can wait inside.
The two us will welcome the guest.
This guest must be treated with respect.
（駿海）今日の客には
失礼があっちゃいけねえ
I'm amazed you stuck with
my old-fashioned training methods.
（駿海）俺の時代遅れのやり方に
よく今日まで ついてきた
It's only right that I reward you.
お前たちには
ご褒美をやらねえとな
I asked him to come here so Hinomaru
can have one, and only one, bout with him.
火ノ丸と
たった一番取るためだけに—
わざわざ来てもらった
Is it really him?
（礼奈）
ウソ…　私でさえ顔は知ってるよ
Even I know who that is!
This is a man the apex of
the pro sumo world, a current yokozuna.
（駿海）大相撲の頂点 現役の—
横綱さまだ
You didn't even last five seconds.
（礼奈）５秒も もたなかったね
It was over before I knew what was going on.
ワケが分からんうちに
終わっちまった
I don't know what I did or what even happened.
何をして 何をされたのかさえも
ウヘヘッ…
なんで うれしそうなのよ
Why are you so happy about that?
So that's the power of a yokozuna.
これが 横綱か
I feel bad that I'm the only one
getting these great experiences.
いいんかな？
ワシばっかり こんないい思いして
I've practiced with
the Shibakiyama Stable,
（火ノ丸）柴木山(しばきやま)部屋から始まり
元横綱の指導に—
trained under a former yokozuna,
and now, I've fought a current yokozuna!
しまいにゃ 現役横綱じゃ
Being this blessed makes me afraid
恵まれ過ぎていて怖くなる
そろそろ
バチでも当たるんじゃねえかってな
something bad's about to happen.
（柴木山）恵まれてる？
He's blessed?
Nothing wrong with that.
（柴木山）いいじゃないですか
（駿海）うん？
Given that he's anything
but blessed in physique,
（柴木山）体格に恵まれなかった分
環境くらいは恵まれたって
he can be blessed by circumstance instead.
Do you really believe that you're blessed?
（駿海）お前は
自分が恵まれてると思うのか？
Hm? Oh, yes, sir.
（火ノ丸）えっ？　あっ はい！
I see! I'm glad to hear that!
そうか　なら 良かった
俺にも いい夢見させてくれよ
Help me dream a good dream.
はい！
Yes, sir!
First, I must conquer high
school sumo this summer!
まずは この夏
高校相撲の頂点 取ってきます！
Thanks, Hori-san.
（小関(おぜき)）ありがとう 堀(ほり)さん
Over here, Hori-chan.
（力士Ｄ）やあ 堀ちゃん
（力士Ｅ）堀ちゃん　俺にも
Hori-chan! Lemme grab one of those.
You're rocking that uniform today.
（力士Ｄ）今日も制服かわいいね
（千鶴子）アア…
What sorta casuals do you usually wear?
（力士Ｅ）
私服って どんなの着るの？
あ〜 メガネもステキ！
Your glasses are the bomb, too.
Have I suddenly become popular?
これがモテ期？
Next Bout  "The Inter High Begins"
No, that can't be right.
いや 違うか